Finding Aid for Peter Pollack papers, 1965-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Peter Pollack papers 1965-2009, 1980-2005
Pollack, Peter, 1939-2010.
4 digital files 1.97 GB or 2,012.93 MB
13 folders (in 2 drawers)
51 tubes
29 linear feet
2011178 Aa 2
Peter Pollack was a landscape architect who primarily worked in the Ann Arbor area. He also served as a professor at the University of Michigan’s School of Natural Resources. The collection includes correspondence, minutes, and working files that document Pollack’s involvement with various urban design and landscape projects in the state of Michigan in addition to his teaching career. The collection also includes drawings and plans for Pollack’s major projects.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection was donated by Eleanor Pollack (donor no. 10510 ) in April 2011.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Peter Pollack, founder of Pollack Design Associates, worked as a landscape architect in the Ann Arbor area. He was heavily involved with local urban design projects. Pollack also served as a member of the faculty at the University of Michigan's School of Natural Resources.
Pollack was born and raised in Philadelphia, PA. He received his bachelor's degree from Pennsylvania State University in 1963 and his master's degree from Harvard University's Graduate School of Design in 1965. While at Harvard he also worked at Sasaki, Dawson, DeMay and Associates. Pollack was named a fellow in landscape architecture by the American Academy in Rome (FAAR) in 1971. He moved to Ann Arbor in 1973 to teach at the University of Michigan's School of Natural Resources. He was also named a fellow by the American Society of Landscape Architects (FASLA) in 1993.
While in Ann Arbor he founded Pollack Design Associates. The firm was involved in the design of Mary Beth Doyle Park and Wetland Preserve, the Furstenberg Interpretive Park, and projects at the former Pfizer site on Plymouth Road. Pollack was heavily involved in projects affiliated with Ann Arbor's Downtown Development Authority, including the development of Ann Arbor's downtown design guidelines and the Ann Arbor Corridor Study.
The Peter Pollack collection (29.5 linear feet, 51 tubes, 13 oversized folders) documents Pollack's professional involvement in the field of landscape architecture. While the collection includes material relating to his teaching career and his involvement in landscape architecture organizations, the bulk of the collection relates to specific projects Pollack worked on. The collection documents his entire career, but includes a greater depth of information related to projects Pollack was involved with in the Ann Arbor area. In addition to the working files for these projects, the collection includes copious sketches drawn by Pollack and official project plans. The material relating to the Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority and the Pfizer campus is particularly strong.
The collection has been arranged into the following series: Administrative Files and Promotional Materials; Project Summaries; Project Files; Teaching Files and Other Activities; Digital Materials; and Videotapes.
Subjects:
Pollack, Peter, 1939-2010.; Ann Arbor Downtown Development Authority.; Ann Arbor Farmer's Market (Mich.); Herman Miller, Inc.; Pfizer Inc.; Pollack Design Associates.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Natural Resources.; Landscape architecture--Michigan.; Landscape design--Michigan.; Rail-trails--Michigan.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Charlevoix (Mich.); Zeeland (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Landscape architecture drawings.; Videotapes.
- Administrative Files and Promotional Materials
  Administrative Files and Promotional Materials (1 linear foot) contains information related to Pollack Design Associates and promotional materials for various projects.
  - American Society of Landscape Architects Application 1961 (Box 1)
  - Awards 1988-1997 (Box 1)
  - Background undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Consultants
    - Architects
      - Herrmann Associates undated (Box 1)
      - Meneghini & Associates undated (Box 1)
      - Richard Neumann 1986 (Box 1)
    - Landscape Architects
      - William J. Johnson Associates 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - Civil engineers
      - All Seasons Consulting Services 1995 (Box 1)
      - Alpha Consulting Engineers undated (Box 1)
      - Boss Engineering Company undated (Box 1)
      - Washtenaw Engineering undated (Box 1)
    - Engineers
      - Neil Adams, Inc. undated (Box 1)
      - CJ Colein 1992 (Box 1)
    - Specialty Consultants
      - Biological Mediation Systems undated (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous consultants undated (Box 1)
      - Janet Frey Talbot undated (Box 1)
      - Design/Economics 1987 (Box 1)
  - Letters of reference 1988-2002 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Projects, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Natural features PR material 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Press releases 1990 (Box 1)
  - Project list undated (Box 1)
  - Resumes undated (Box 1)
  - Staff photographs, color and black-and-white (Box 1)
  - Staff profiles undated (Box 1)
  - Wetland assessment services marketing 1991-1995 (Box 1)
- Project Summaries
  The Project Summaries (3.5 linear feet) series contains project lists and brief summaries of projects Pollack worked on, in addition to more comprehensive project reports for projects Pollack worked on in the state of Michigan.
  - Project Profiles
    - Job lists 1984-1991, 8 folders (Box 1)
    - Alpena Bi-path (Alpena, MI) 1995 (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor DDA (Ann Arbor, MI) 1985, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor Depot (Ann Arbor, MI) 1980 (Box 2)
    - Huron River Corridor (Ann Arbor, MI) 1987 (Box 2)
    - Pedestrian improvements (Ann Arbor, MI) 1984 (Box 2)
    - Plan for Parks, Recreation, and Open Spaces (Ann Arbor, MI) 1981 (Box 2)
    - Avis Farms (Pittsfield Township, MI) 1991 (Box 2)
    - Bandemer Park (Ann Arbor, MI) 1992 (Box 2)
    - Beach Lake (Livingston County, MI) 1991 (Box 2)
    - Broadway Street intersection (Ann Arbor, MI) 1980 (Box 2)
    - Burns Park School (Ann Arbor) 1993 (Box 2)
    - Canton Recreation Complex (Canton, MI) 1991 (Box 2)
    - Caseville County Park (Huron County, MI) 1997 (Box 2)
    - Marina and Park Plan (Charlevoix, MI) 2002 (Box 2)
    - Church of Latter-Day Saints (Ann Arbor, MI) 1993 (Box 2)
    - Congregational Church (Ann Arbor) undated (Box 2)
    - Crosswinds Marsh (Wayne County, MI) undated (Box 2)
    - Elizabeth Dean Promenade (Ann Arbor, MI) 1985 (Box 2)
    - Skyline Renewal (Denver, CO) undated (Box 2)
    - Dexter Community Schools (Dexter, MI) 1993 (Box 2)
    - Dundee Village Center (Dundee, MI) undated (Box 2)
    - Ernst Property (1991) (Box 2)
    - First Congregational Church (Alpena, MI) 1976 (Box 2)
    - Ford Heritage Park (Ypsilanti, MI) 1989 (Box 2)
    - Furstenberg Park (Ann Arbor, MI) 1991-1992 (Box 2)
    - Gandy Dancer (Ann Arbor, MI) 1976 (Box 2)
    - Sports Park and Ski Hill (Gladstone, MI) 1995 (Box 2)
    - Grand River Streetscape (Meridian, MI) 1995 (Box 2)
    - Green Oaks Golf Course (Ypsilanti, MI) 1989 (Box 2)
    - Haithco Recreation Area (Saginaw County, MI) 1989 (Box 2)
    - Hall Road Village (Hamburg Township, MI) 1994 (Box 2)
    - Hayden House (Ann Arbor, MI) 1986 (Box 2)
    - Herman Miller
      - Powdercoat Technology 1991 (Box 2)
      - SQA (Holland, MI) 1995, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Hillsdale Trail (Hillsdale, MI) 1990 (Box 2)
    - Huntley Cove (Webster Township, MI) 1989 (Box 2)
    - Huron River Bikeway (Ann Arbor, MI) 1984 (Box 2)
    - Huron River Recreation Corridor (Ypsilanti, MI) 1988 (Box 2)
    - Independence Lake Park (Washtenaw County, MI) undated (Box 2)
    - Jackson Road Design Study (Scio Township, MI) 1989 (Box 2)
    - La Plaisance Industrial Park (Monroe County, MI) 1985 (Box 2)
    - Lighthouse Park (Huron County, MI) 1994 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Schools (Washtenaw County, MI) 1984 (Box 2)
    - Maineway Mall (Portland, ME) undated (Box 2)
    - Mallard Landing (Green Oak Township, MI) 1990 (Box 2)
    - Cedar Street (Manistique, MI) 1995 (Box 2)
    - Mills Property (Ann Arbor, MI) 1986 (Box 2)
    - Montebemer Park undated (Box 2)
    - Moores Park (Lansing, MI) 1991 (Box 2)
    - Murphy Farm (Saginaw, MI) 1988 (Box 2)
    - North Bay Park (Ypsilanti, MI) undated (Box 2)
    - Oakbrook Park (Superior Township, MI) 1991 (Box 2)
    - Oakland Oaks Commerce Center (Wixom, MI) 1985 (Box 2)
    - Parkins Gravel Pit (Oxford Township, MI) 1982 (Box 2)
    - Pepperwood (Grand Blanc, MI) 1991 (Box 2)
    - Pere Marquette Rail-Trail (Midland, MI) 1992, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Plymouth Green Technology Center (Ann Arbor, MI) 2000 (Box 2)
    - Sault Ste. Marie (Sault Ste. Marie, MI) 2000 (Box 2)
    - Scio Town Center (Scio Township, MI) 1989 (Box 2)
    - Warner-Lambert/Parke-Davis (Ann Arbor, MI) 1993 (Box 2)
    - West Bloomfield Trail Network (West Bloomfield, MI) undated (Box 2)
    - West Willow Park (Ypsilanti, MI) 1986 (Box 2)
    - River Street redevelopment (Ypsilanti, MI) 1986 (Box 2)
  - Project Reports
    - Ann Arbor
      - Ann Arbor's Central Area: A Vision and Agenda for the Future 1987 (Box 3)
      - Ann Arbor Corridor Study 1983 (Box 3)
      - Ann Arbor Corridor Study -- Summary Report 1983 (Box 3)
      - Ann Arbor Depot 1979 (Box 3)
      - Ann Arbor Downtown Plan 1988 (Box 3)
      - Ann Arbor Trolley Feasibility Study 1977 (Box 3)
      - Argo Framework Study 1993 (Box 3)
      - Buhr Park -- Infrastructure Improvements 2007 (Box 3)
      - City of Ann Arbor Bike Path Study 1973 (Box 3)
      - Downtown Ann Arbor Development and Conservation Strategy 1975 (Box 3)
      - General Development Plan for the City of Ann Arbor 1973 (Box 3)
      - Hayden House Preliminary Land Use Study 1986 (Box 3)
      - Hidden Lake 1987 (Box 3)
      - Huron River Corridor: Detroit Edison and Mich Con Parcels 1987 (Box 3)
      - Huron Valley Girl Scout Council 1986 (Box 3)
      - Leslie Laboratories 1983 (Box 3)
      - Master Plan for Pedestrian Improvements 1985 (Box 3)
      - Master Plan for Pedestrian Improvements -- Preliminary Draft Materials 1983 (Box 3)
      - Old Fourth Ward Historic District 1982 (Box 3)
      - Pedestrian Improvements Project -- Phase 1 1983 (Box 3)
      - Pedestrian Improvements Project -- Phase 1B 1984 (Box 3)
      - Pedestrian Improvements Project -- Phase 2 1985 (Box 3)
      - Plan for Park, Recreation, and Open Space 1981 (Box 3)
      - Plan for Solving Circulation Problems 1977 (Box 3)
      - Proposed Area Plan for the Mills Property 1985 (Box 3)
      - Urban Design Workbook for Huron St, Division St, and Fifth Ave 2004 (Box 3)
      - Vacant Land Inventory 1978 (Box 3)
      - Zoning Chapter (Box 3)
    - Ypsilanti
      - Eastern Michigan University -- A Concept Plan for Campus 2004 (Box 3)
      - Huron River Corridor 1986 (Box 3)
      - Non-Motorized Trail System 1997 (Box 3)
      - Non-Motorized Pathway System -- Updated 1999 (Box 4)
      - Plan for Parks and Recreation 1985 (Box 4)
      - Plan for Parks and Recreation 1989 (Box 4)
      - Plan for Parks and Recreation 1991 (Box 4)
      - West Willow Park -- Land and Water Fund Pre-Application 1985 (Box 4)
      - West Willow Park -- Phase 2 1986 (Box 4)
    - Washtenaw County
      - Fiscal Impacts of Growth 1982 (Box 4)
      - Huntley Cove -- Webster Township 1989 (Box 4)
      - Huron Valley Bikeway 1976 (Box 4)
      - Huron-Whittaker Corridor 2000 (Box 4)
      - Jackson Road Design Study -- Scio Township 1990 (Box 4)
      - Parks and Recreation Plan 1985 (Box 4)
      - Parks and Recreation Plan 1992 (Box 4)
      - Parks and Recreation Plan 1998 (Box 4)
      - Relocation and Restoration of the Original Superior Township Hall 1985 (Box 4)
      - Scio Town Center Plaza 1988 (Box 4)
      - Transportation Profile 1985 (Box 4)
      - Addison Oaks County Park: 1992 Master Plan -- Oakland County, 1992 (Box 4)
      - BASF South Waterfront Recreational Design -- Wyandotte 1992 (Box 4)
      - Central Park Master Plan Resource Group Meetings -- Ingham County 1986 (Box 4)
      - Concepts for a Waterfront Village -- Gladstone 1994 (Box 4)
      - Corridor Design Plan -- Alpena 1995 (Box 4)
      - Costal Zone Management Study -- Rogers City 1980 (Box 4)
      - Feasibility Study for the Potential Bicycle Path Projects -- Beverly Hills 1985 (Box 4)
      - Hall Road Village -- Livingston County 1994 (Box 4)
      - Hillsdale Pride: The Baw Beese Trail Systems -- Hillsdale 1990 (Box 4)
      - Huron County Nature Center -- Huron County 1991 (Box 4)
      - Huron County Parks and Recreation Plan -- Huron County 1991 (Box 4)
      - Kent County Millennium Vision -- Kent County 2006 (Box 4)
      - Land Use Plan -- Monroe County 2000 (Box 4)
      - LaPlaisance Industrial Park Land Use and Development Plan -- Monroe County 1985 (Box 5)
      - Lighthouse Park Trustfund Application -- Huron County 1995 (Box 5)
      - Mallard Lake -- Livingston County 1990 (Box 5)
      - Manistee Lake Management Plan: Summary Report -- Manistee County 1982 (Box 5)
      - Manistee Lake Implementation Manual -- Manistee County 1982 (Box 5)
      - Master Plan: Central Park -- Ingham County 1987 (Box 5)
      - Master Plan for Lighthouse Park -- Huron County 1994 (Box 5)
      - Murphy Farm: A Master Plan for Physical Restoration and Environmental Education -- Saginaw 1988 (Box 5)
      - Oakland Oaks Commerce Center -- Farmington 1985 (Box 5)
      - Parks and Recreation Master Plan -- Westland 2002 (Box 5)
      - Portage Street Improvements -- Sault Ste Marie 1998 (Box 5)
      - S & H Lake Park-Saginaw County 1987 (Box 5)
      - Shelden Sculpture Garden -- Detroit 1982 (Box 5)
      - William H. Haithco Recreation Center -- Saginaw County 1988 (Box 5)
    - Consortium of International Earth Science Information Network Site Evaluation and Investigation 1992 (Box 5)
- Project Files
  The Project Files (20.5 linear feet, 51 tubes, 13 oversize folders) have been arranged into the following sub-series: Ann Arbor Projects, Herman Miller Projects, Pfizer Campus Projects, and Other Michigan Projects. Each subseries has been divided into Textual Files and Drawings and Plans. Drawings and Plans includes items in both folders and tubes. Folders are largely comprised of pencil drawings and sketches, while tubes are largely composed of project plans.
  - Ann Arbor Projects
    The Ann Arbor Projects (9.5 linear feet, 15 tubes, 6 oversize folders) subseries contains correspondence, minutes, permits, presentations, and working files related to various projects Pollack worked on in Ann Arbor. These projects include the Allen Creek Greenway Task Force; the Ann Arbor Corridor Study; the Farmer's Market commission; the Parks, Recreation, and Open Space Plan; the Commission on Art in Public Places; Downtown Design Guidelines; the Downtown Development Authority, Fuller Road; Furstenberg Park; Gandy Dancer; Huron-Division-Fifth St; Liberty Plaza; Mary Beth Doyle Park; the State Street Urban Design Project; and the University of Michigan. The subseries also contains sketches, plans, and drawings related to Pollack's projects in Ann Arbor.
    - Textual Records
      - Allen Creek Greenway Task Force (ACGTF)
        - Maps and Drawings (Box 5)
        - History and Site Booklet (Box 5)
        - Findings and Recommendations, Final (Box 5)
        - Findings and Recommendations, Draft (Box 5)
        - Meetings 2005 (Box 5)
        - Workshop 1B, Site Specific Data (Box 5)
        - Meetings July-September 2006 (Box 5)
        - General Information (Box 5)
        - Workshop 1A April 22, 2006 (Box 5)
        - Floodway (Box 5)
        - Tonight's Meeting May 17, 2006 (Box 5)
        - Materials for Meeting August 2, 2006 (Box 5)
        - "Help Shape Allen Creek Greenway," Workbook (Box 5)
        - Greenway Plan (Box 5)
        - Correspondence (Box 5)
        - Powerpoint Presentations (Box 5)
        - Public Participation materials (Box 6)
        - Task Force Handouts (Box 6)
        - Principles (Box 6)
        - Interactive Public Design Project (Box 6)
        - Public Process (Box 6)
        - Supplemental Appendix, 4 folders (Box 6)
        - Washtenaw Avenue 2005-2009 (Box 6)
        - Preliminary Planning (Box 6)
        - News clippings (Box 6)
        - City of Ann Arbor Parcel Options (Box 6)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
        - Resolution Creating a New Greenway Taskforce (Box 6)
        - Communication, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Ann Arbor Corridor Study
        - Original Artwork (Box 6)
        - Composite of Design Guidelines 1983 (Box 6)
        - Final Draft Report 1983, 2 folders (Box 6)
        - Draft Report 1983, 2 folders (Box 6)
        - Preliminary Drafts 1983 (Box 6)
        - Proposal for Services 1981 (Box 6)
      - Ann Arbor Farmer's Market Commission
        - Binder: Minutes and agenda 2005 (Box 7)
        - Market Commission Background (Box 7)
        - Farmer's Market Working Files 2005 (Box 7)
        - Farmer's Market Master Plan (draft) 2004 (Box 7)
        - Friends of the Market 2005 (Box 7)
        - Agendas and Correspondence 2005-2006 (Box 7)
        - Correspondence 2005 (Box 7)
        - Meeting Agenda June 15, 2006 (Box 7)
        - Market Commission Working Files, 3 folders (Box 7)
        - Information on Other Michigan Farmer's Markets (Box 7)
        - Site Planning (Box 7)
        - Complaints 2009 (Box 7)
        - Seniority 2008 (Box 7)
        - Market Commission (Box 7)
        - Public Market (Box 7)
        - Stark Complaint (Box 7)
        - Former Market Commission (Box 8)
        - Market Commission, J. Black (Box 8)
        - Market Commission, Current (Box 8)
        - Advisory Commission (Box 8)
        - Boundary and Topographic Survey 2003 (Box 8)
        - Background Information (Box 8)
        - Farmers Market Working Files (Box 8)
        - Presentation (Box 8)
        - Public Meeting (Box 8)
      - Ann Arbor Parks, Recreation and Open Space Plan
        - Award Submission 1982 (Box 8)
        - Final Draft and Appendix 1981 (Box 8)
        - Park Maintenance Plan 1976 (Box 8)
        - Proposed Parks and Open Space Plan 1978 (Box 8)
        - Summary Plan 1981 (Box 8)
      - Bandemer Park Plans 1993 (Box 8)
      - Commission on Art in Public Places (CAPP)
        - Ann Arbor Public Art Commission 2004-2008 (Box 8)
        - Annual Report 2003 (Box 8)
        - Arts Alliance (Box 8)
        - CAPP meeting minutes 2004 (Box 8)
        - CAPP Planning 2005 (Box 8)
        - Community interviews 2003 (Box 8)
        - Community resource book (Box 8)
        - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 9)
        - Grant proposal (Box 9)
        - Jury process (Box 9)
        - Master plan 2004 (Box 9)
        - Master plan RFP documents 2003 (Box 9)
        - MDOT Slide Presentation 1994 (Box 9)
        - Off the Wall Gallery (Box 9)
        - Park Advisory Commission meeting 2004 (Box 9)
        - Plan preparation (Box 9)
      - Downtown Ann Arbor Design Guidelines
        - Ann Arbor Downtown Plan 2008 (Box 9)
        - Comments from City Website 2009 (Box 9)
        - Guidelines Drafts 2008-2010, 3 folders (Box 9)
        - Memos 2006-2007 (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
        - Planning commission meetings 2008 (Box 9)
        - Recommended Policy Framework for Downtown Ann Arbor 2005 (Box 9)
        - Working Files, 3 folders (Box 9)
        - Workshops (Box 9)
      - Downtown Development Authority (DDA)
        - Agendas
          - 1986 (Box 9)
          - 1987, 2 folders (Box 9)
          - 1988, 3 folders (Box 9)
          - 1989 (Box 9)
          - 2002 (Box 10)
          - 2003, 2 folders (Box 10)
          - 2004 (Box 10)
        - Meeting Agendas and Minutes (Box 10)
        - Misc. Correspondence (Box 10)
        - Huron/Fifth/Division, 2 folders (Box 10)
        - Pedestrian Improvements Master Plan materials, 6 folders (Box 10)
        - Pedestrian Improvements 4th Avenue (Box 10)
        - News Clippings (Box 10)
        - Preliminary Concepts (Box 10)
        - Contract (Box 10)
        - Preliminary Draft Materials (Box 10)
        - Walt's Letter (Box 10)
        - Light Fixtures, 2 folders (Box 10)
        - Memos and Attachments (Box 10)
        - Questionnaire (Box 10)
        - Projects Evaluation (Box 10)
        - Correspondence (Box 11)
        - Details (Box 11)
        - Master Plan, Construction Standards (Box 11)
        - Liberty Street, 3 folders (Box 11)
        - Master Plan, Base Maps (Box 11)
        - Graphics (Box 11)
        - Maps (Box 11)
        - Liberty Street Evaluation (Box 11)
        - Liberty Street Estimate (Box 11)
        - Library Lot (Box 11)
        - S. Fourth Street Estimate (Box 11)
        - Construction Engineering 2001 (Box 11)
        - Pollack Designs Billing Summaries 1983-1985 (Box 11)
        - Ann Arbor Transit Authority (AATA) Downtown Transfer Center Plans (Box 11)
        - Ann Arbor Walking Tours (Box 11)
        - Attachments 2003 (Box 11)
        - "R" Items 2003, 2005 (Box 11)
        - "The Ann Arbor Central Area -- A Program for the Future," 1987 (Box 11)
        - Downtown Ann Arbor Revitalization Plan Maps 2005 (Box 11)
      - Fuller Road Projects
        - Fuller Road/Fuller Park Site Information (Box 11)
        - Fuller Road/Maiden Lane Intersection
          - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 11)
          - Plans 2006 (Box 11)
          - Roundabouts research (Box 11)
        - Fuller Road Re-Alignment Wetland Mitigation
          - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 11)
          - Monitoring Report and Drawings (Box 11)
          - Lee Skabelund's Notes (Box 11)
          - Revised Specifications (Box 12)
          - Wetland Mitigation, 2 folders (Box 12)
          - Wetland Slides 2000 (Box 12)
          - Reports 1998-2002 (Box 12)
          - Photographs and Slides 2001 (Box 12)
          - Contract Documents for Fuller Road Wetland Mitigation and Tree Planting Project, File No. 94048 1994 (Box 12)
          - Specifications 1992-1999 (scattered) (Box 12)
        - Glen/Fuller
          - Award Submission (Box 12)
          - Fuller/Glen Transit Project (Box 12)
          - Glenn/Fuller/Geddes Study 1981 (Box 12)
          - Glen/Fuller Project Draft Negative Declaration 1980 (Box 12)
          - Glen Fuller Project Environmental Assessment 1981, 2 folders (Box 12)
          - Photographs, 3 folders (Box 12)
          - Plans and Drawings (Box 12)
          - Project planning (Box 12)
          - Drawings (Box 12)
      - Furstenberg Park
        - Award Submission (Box 12)
        - Furstenberg Park Development Request for Proposals 1990 (Box 12)
        - Reconnaissance 1991 (Box 12)
      - Gandy Dancer
        - Project Files 1976-1978 (Box 12)
        - Photographs (Box 12)
        - Specifications for Site Development 1976 (Box 12)
      - Huron, Division, Fifth streets (Ann Arbor) (Box 13)
        - ASLA Award Submission 2005 (Box 13)
        - Presentations 2005 (Box 13)
        - Project Proposal 2003 (Box 13)
        - Public Hearing 2998 (Box 13)
        - Urban Design Workbook 2004 (Box 13)
      - Liberty Plaza
        - Submittals (Box 13)
        - Chronological File
          - March 2003 (Box 13)
          - May-June, 2003 (Box 13)
          - January-February, 2003 (Box 13)
          - August-December, 2002 (Box 13)
          - December 2001-July 2002 (Box 13)
        - Contract Documents for the Liberty Plaza Improvements 2003 (Box 13)
        - Specifications for Bidding March 13, 2003 (Box 13)
        - Specifications for Review 2003 (Box 13)
        - Community Meetings 2002 (Box 13)
        - Construction Meeting notes 2003 (Box 13)
      - Mary Beth Doyle Park (Brown Park) Detention Basin
        - Chronological File
          - March-April, 2003 (Box 13)
          - May-August, 2003 (Box 13)